# **ZHENGYANG HUANG**

- email: zhuang0buo@outlook.com - phone: +1 757-719-6047

- project highlights: https://zhengyang-huang.me/Project-Highlights.pdf

- website: <a href="https://zhengyang-huang.me/">https://zhengyang-huang.me/</a>

- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/zhengyang-huang/

Zhengyang is a new media artist currently based in LA. He is specialized in creating experience and design contents in different media including website, illustration, 2D/3D graphic design, and video production. Besides his in-house and freelance experience, he has over 3 years of experience in self-initiated independent or collaborative creative projects, in which he solves creative and design problems such as how to keep people engaged, how to turn viewers into participants, and how to have people follow up through the whole project.

## **EDUCATION**

UCLA - MFA, Design | Media Arts - Los Angeles, CA College of William and Mary - BA, Studio Arts - 3D - Williamsburg, VA June 2021 May 2019

### **SKILL**

- Web and Game Interactives: HTML, Javascript, CSS, JQuery, Wordpress, Lottie Animation for Web, CSS/JS UI animation, Webpack, Adobe XD, Unity3D, Unity C#, Processing, Arduino, Git, Github;
- **3D/2D Graphics:** Blender, Maya, VR video, Reality Capture, R3D Wrap, RunwayML, Adobe Illustrator, Substance Painter, Photoshop, InDesign, Figma;
- Videography and Motion Graphics: Adobe
   AfterEffects, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe Audition,
   Audacity;
- Soft Skills: Concept building, Communication Skill, Teamwork, Problem-Solving Ability, Flexibility, Time Management;

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Visual Designer / Videographer - Global Talent Link · Contract August 2021 - Present

- Conceptualized brand images and stories, created prototypes and developed a whole new set of visual assets to represent mission statement, convey brand narratives, and add warmth in visuals to show a sense of community;
- Revamped company website content and graphics on Wordpress, collaborated with a web developer and the marketing team to develop new layouts, graphics, interaction, and writings;
- Designed landing page with Lottie SVG animation and responsive features developed with HTML, CSS, Javascript;
- Created a marketing video with animated assets, motion effects which fully utilizes company footages and removes stock images;
- Collaborated with service team and developed a new slide deck with illustrations and scripts that represents brand image and introduces company services;
- Illustrated community flyer to be produced both in print and online, with QR code tracking included for marketing purpose;

## Freelance Web Design/Development - Kindred Spirit

Feb 2022 - Present

- Iterated through different design and ideas for website improvements;
- Redesigned website user flow, content, and created web prototypes with Adobe XD, Illustrator, and 3D software Blender;
- Improve web page layouts, backgrounds, graphics, and create new interactions, images, and web assets with customized HTML/CSS on Squarespace;
- Created CSS animation for work sample page

Lecturer - UCLA - Los Angeles, CA

June 2021 - August 2021

- Taught *DESMA 24 Motion* (<a href="https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Summer21/24/">https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Summer21/24/</a>), a course in theory and practice of motion graphics including video making and editing, 3D modeling and animation, as well as GAN generated images;
- Led learning sessions and made tutorials for Autodesk Maya, Adobe After Effects, Premiere Pro, and RunwayML;
- Led lectures, discussions, screenings, critiques to expand knowledge and develop critical thinking on moving images;

## Teaching assistant - UCLA - Los Angeles, CA

October 2019 - June 2021

- Led discussion sessions to expand course materials and have more discussions on media art history and practice;
- Designed and created websites to manage and share materials and resources as well as showcasing student work;
- Assisted instructors in and out of class, coordinated meetings, supported students on projects and assignments;
- List of courses:
  - o 09/2019 12/2019 Media Arts Introduction
  - o 01/2020 03/2020 Motion (https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Winter20/24/)
  - o 09/2020 12/2020 Special Topics: Cultural Appropriation With Machine Learning
  - o 09/2020 12/2020 Design Culture
  - o 01/2021 03/2021 Motion
  - o 03/2021 06/2021 Video (https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Spring21/153/)

## **EXHIBITION**

2021

- *Air, Water, Fire*, SLSA 2021 (Society for Literature, Science, and The Arts,), Penny W. Stamps School of Art & Design at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, <a href="https://stamps.umich.edu/events/slsa-exhibit">https://stamps.umich.edu/events/slsa-exhibit</a>, 10/2021
- Air, Water, Fire, in group show The Last Online Show, D|MA MFA show, http://projects.dma.ucla.edu/exhibitions/mfa2021/2020/10/13/zhengyang/, 05/2021
- Air, solo show in collaboration, online, D|MA, 02/2021

2020

- Share Screen, D|MA Fall Preview Show, <a href="https://projects.dma.ucla.edu/exhibitions/sharescreen/">https://projects.dma.ucla.edu/exhibitions/sharescreen/</a>, 10/2020
  - Besides showing work, I also developed and designed the landing page of the exhibition website

2019

- Image at Surface, solo show at Linda Matney Gallery, Williamsburg VA, 04/2019
- Capstone Show, group show at Williamsburg Contemporary Art Center, Williamsburg VA, 02/2019
- A Sense of Occasion, group show at Andrews Gallery, Williamsburg VA, 05/2019

2018

Transposition: Asian Cultures, group show at Linda Matney Gallery, Williamsburg VA, 02/2018

## **PUBLICATION**

- Image at Surface, Artsy, 2019
- Transparency, Acropolis Art Journal, 2017
- Solidarity, Acropolis Art Journal, 2017
- Chaos // Disorder, Acropolis Art Journal, 2016

### **GRANTS AND AWARDS**

2021

- Clifton Webb Scholarship, School of Arts & Architecture, UCLA, 01/2021 06/2021
- Dr. Hyuman Eugene Oxman & Frieda Dreyer Oxman Fellowship Fund, School of Arts & Architecture, UCLA, 01/2021
   06/2021

2020

Dean's Graduate Scholarship, D|MA, School of Arts & Architecture, UCLA, 09/2020 - 06/2021

# 2019

• Alumni Association Award, College of William and Mary, 06/2019

#### 2018

- Honors Research Project Fellowship, College of William and Mary, 08/2018 05/2019
- The Joseph Palin Thorley Memorial Scholarship for the Study of Art, College of William and Mary
- Initiated as a member of Phi Beta Kappa, Alpha of Virginia at the College of William and Mary, 12/05/2018 2017
- The Joseph Palin Thorley Memorial Scholarship for the Study of Art, College of William and Mary
- Roy R. Charles Grant for Semester Independent Study, College of William and Mary